Sampson County CR.087
State Archives of North Carolina
- Marriage, Divorce, and Vital Statistics, 1869-2009; CR.087.6; Sampson County (N.C.). Clerk of Superior Court.
  - Alien Registration Record [Microfilm], C.087.60000; 103; Sampson County (N.C.) (Reel Alien Registration Record, Reeldtl Alien Registration Record)
  - Naturalization, Record of [Microfilm], C.087.60000; 128; Sampson County (N.C.) (Reel Naturalization, Record of)
  - Adoption Records [Microfilm], C.087.60000; 25; Sampson County (N.C.) (Reel Adoption Records)
- Tax Records, 1789-1922; CR.087.7; 287.73; 287.73.1; CR.087.703.1; Sampson County (N.C.). Clerk of Superior Court. (Box Miscellaneous Tax Records)
  Contains miscellaneous tax records relating to taxation, specifically actions against persons failing to list taxes, 1879-1922 (broken series); application of Eliza Bibb for repayment of direct tax, 1894; civil actions concerning taxes, 1885, 1888, 1911, 1913; criminal action concerning taxes, State vs. Board of County Commissioners of Sampson County, 1908; levies on land for taxes, 1872, 1874, 1875, 1896; list of taxes, 1871-1872; sheriff's allowance for insolvent taxables, 1789.
  See series 4, Land and Property Taxes, for Inheritance Tax Records and series 5, Estate Records, for Land Sales for Taxes, if available.
  - Tax List [Microfilm], C.087.70000; 99; Sampson County (N.C.) (Reel Tax List)
  - Tax Scrolls [Microfilm], C.087.70000; 100; Sampson County (N.C.) (Reel Tax Scrolls, Reel Bryant, Susan P. - Wiggins, Pauline B. Mrs., Reel Williams, James Lofton - Pope, Walter)
  - Tax Maps [Microfilm], C.087.70000; 195; Sampson County (N.C.) (Reel Tax Maps)
- Wills, 1778-1953; CR.087.8; 287.74; 287.74.1; CR.087.801.1- CR.087.801.20; Sampson County (N.C.). Clerk of Superior Court. (Box Wills)
  Adams-Ziegler. Includes record of wills and original wills arranged alphabetically by decedent. Many of the older record of wills may also record estates matters (inventories, accounts of sale, and final settlements) and deeds. Recording of wills on a regular basis began about 1820. At a later date, wills that had been proved prior to 1820 as well as wills that had not be probated were entered into a record book identified as Will Book A. Excerpt from North Carolina Wills: A Testator Index, 1665-1900, by Thornton W. Mitchell (Raleigh: 1987).
  - Wills, Record of [Microfilm], C.087.80000; 12; Sampson County (N.C.) (Reel Wills, Record of)
  - Index to Wills [Microfilm], C.087.80000; 14; Sampson County (N.C.) (Reel Index to Wills)
  - Index to Wills-Devisees [Microfilm], C.087.80000; 101; Sampson County (N.C.) (Reel Index to Wills-Devisees)
- Election Records, 1878-1926; CR.087.9; 287.87; Sampson County (N.C.). Clerk of Superior Court.
  This series may include Election Returns, in volumes and boxes; Permanent Registration of Voters (grandfather clause registrations, 1902-1908) volumes; and Poll Books deposited with the clerk of Superior Court. It may also include minutes of the county Board of Elections.
  Boxes may include civil and criminal actions concerning elections (see series 3, Court Records, for civil and criminal case files, if available).
  - Record of Elections, 1878-1926; CR.087.912; 287.87.1; CR.087.912.1- CR.087.912.3; Sampson County (N.C.). Clerk of Superior Court. (Item Record of Elections)
    Volumes span the following dates: 1878-1912 1906-1916 1920-1926.
  - Permanent Voter Registration, 1902-1908; CR.087.912; 287.87.2; CR.087.912.4; Sampson County (N.C.). Clerk of Superior Court. (Item Permanent Voter Registration)
  - Elections, Record of [Microfilm], C.087.90000; 126; Sampson County (N.C.) (Reel Elections, Record of)
- Miscellaneous Records, 1798-1928; CR.087.10; Sampson County (N.C.). Clerk of Superior Court.
  This series may include Armed Forces Discharges; Cemetery Records; Coroner's Inquests and Reports; Military Records; Pension Records; Personal Accounts; Road Records and Reports; School Records; and truly miscellaneous records collected from various county agencies and offices. Miscellaneous Records boxes may also include records from all other county series that were of insufficient quantity to make a full box.
  - Road and Railroad Records, 1829-1921; CR.087.925; 287.100; Sampson County (N.C.). Clerk of Superior Court.
    Road Records may include volumes or boxes of records concerning appointment of road overseers, reports on condition of roads, and petitions for new roads. Boxes may also include criminal actions concerning negligence of overseers and claims against the county for services on the roads. Records concerning bridges and railroads are also included in this series, usually as separate subseries. Volumes may also include minutes of the county highway or good roads commission.
    - Railroad Records, 1869-1921; CR.087.925; 287.100.1; CR.087.925.1- CR.087.925.4; Sampson County (N.C.). Clerk of Superior Court. (Box Railroad Records)
    - Record of Appointment of Road Overseers, 1829-1868; CR.087.925; 287.100.2; CR.087.925.5- CR.087.925.7; Sampson County (N.C.). Clerk of Court of Pleas and Quarter Sessions. (Item Record of Appointment of Road Overseers)
      Volumes span the following dates: 1829-1842 1843-1849 1849-1868
  - Miscellaneous Records, 1798-1928; CR.087.928; 287.103; 287.103.1; CR.087.928.1- CR.087.928.4; Sampson County (N.C.). Clerk of Superior Court. (Box Miscellaneous Records)
    In box CR.087.928.1: admittance of G.W. Britt to the Bar as an attorney, 1879; affidavits of Michael J. Bell (1863) and W.H. Darden (1875); agreement, Allmand T. Jackson to James K. Morisey, 1869; Aman Grocery Company, partnership, 1915; appointments of justices of the peace, 1866-1869; apprentice bonds and records, 1829-1897 (broken series); authorization to issue marriage license to Octavia J. Vann, minor, 1868; bridge records, no date, 1847-1868 (broken series); certificate of copartnership of the P.M. Bullard Company, 1918; certification of seeing notice by Parish, Roberson, and Treadwell, 1839; coroners' inquests, no date, 1830-1923 (broken series).
    In box CR.087.928.2: correspondence, L.E. Warren to Jane Bradshaw, 1903-1906 (see Sampson County criminal action papers, 1906); correspondence, R.F. Pettigrew to the Raleigh News and Observer concerning Senator Marion Butler, 1910; correspondence to the clerks of superior court, 1870-1913 (broken series); county accounts, 1836-1910 (broken series); deputation of William B. Draughon in office of clerk of county court, 1864; docket (rough), 1 page, 1806; election records, no date, 1800, 1801, 1803, 1891, 1898; fragment of document signed by Hardy Holmes, clerk of court, 1801; governors' orders appointing judges to hold terms of court, 1886, 1898, 1903; grand jury reports, no date, 1868-1896 (broken series); in re: the custody of Mary Matilda Autry, 1875; in re: the legitimation of Malcolmb James Register, 1905; in re: the legitimation of Malinda Jane Rily, 1897; in re: Little Coharie Drainage District, 1915; insolvent debtors, 1854-1868 (broken series); insurance policies to various parties, 1870, 1871, 1891; inventories and accounts (unidentified), no date, 1798.
    In box C.R.087.928.3: list of jurors, 1874; lunacy records, 1821-1905 (broken series); marriage contract, Thomas K. Bryan and others vs. William A. Faison and others, 1878; mill records, no date, 1813, 1854; notice of adoption of a corporate seal for the Board of Commissioners of Sampson County, 1888; oaths of officials, 1872-1928 (broken series); officials' bonds, 1834-1892 (broken series); order to sheriff to carry out execution (defendent unknown), no date; orders to issue licenses to retail spiritous liquors, 1840, 1841; pardon of Elias Pearsall, 1875; pardon of June Baggett and John McIlwame, 1892; personal accounts, no date, 1801-1921 (broken series); petition of Amos Maynard to be discharged from prison, 1872; petition of Simion Corbett for restoration of citizenship, 1892; petition of Taylor Faison for restoration of citizenship, 1896; petitions for naturalization, 1844, 1860, 1896, 1908; petitions for writs of habeas corpus, 1877-1920 (broken series); petitions to be discharged as insolvents, no date, 1871-1903 (broken series); powers of attorney, 1862, 1872, 1886, 1897, 1904; prison bounds of Sampson County, 1839; protest of H. Brockett, 1836; record of strays, 1827-1868; reports of marriage licenses issued, 1883, 1901, 1902; resignation of G.C. Highsmith as a justice of the peace, 1898; resolution on the death of Hardy Lucian Holmes, no date; resolution on the retirement of Judge David L. Ward, 1910.
    In box C.R.087.928.4: road records, no date, 1799-1914 (broken series); school records, no date, 1880-1916 (broken series); slave records, 1832-1869 (broken series); solicitors' reports, 1848-1905 (broken series); testimony concerning Ann M. Reynolds application for a Civil War widow's pension, 1887; wardens of the poor, 1830-1848 (broken series).
  - Road Overseers [Microfilm], C.087.100000; 130; Sampson County (N.C.) (Reel Road Overseers)
  - Armed Forces Discharges, Record of [Microfilm], C.087.100000; 7; Sampson County (N.C.) (Reel Armed Forces Discharges, Record of)
  - Index to Armed Forces Discharges [Microfilm], C.087.100000; 105; Sampson County (N.C.) (Reel Index to Armed Forces Discharges)
  - N. C. Cumulative Records [Microfilm], C.087.100000; 177; Sampson County (N.C.) (Reel N. C. Cumulative Records)
  - Index to Miscellaneous [Microfilm], C.087.100000; 113; Sampson County (N.C.) (Reel Index to Miscellaneous)